■ agrawalk@stanford.edu | 🏕 www.ketan.me | 🖸 ketan0 | 🛅 ketan-jay-agrawal | 💆 _ketan0

Summary_

I'm a master's student in Computer Science at Stanford using artificial intelligence in human-centered applications, such as developmental psych, mental healthcare, and human-computer interaction. My outputs include published research, an impactful web application at Amazon, and a hackathon-winning smart glove. In my free time, I enjoy extending Emacs, experimenting in my digital laboratory, and playing with my cats.

Education

Stanford University Stanford, CA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (AI)

Jan. 2021 - Jun. 2022 (expected)

• GPA: 3.89/4.00

· Planned Coursework: Reinforcement Learning, Deep Generative Models, Graph Machine Learning

Stanford University Stanford, CA

B.S. IN SYMBOLIC SYSTEMS (AI)

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

• GPA: 3.82/4.00

• Relevant Coursework: Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Probabilistic Programming

Research Experience _____

Partnership in Al-Assisted Care Stanford, CA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jan. 2020 - present

· Design AI tools for automated mental health assessment under Prof. Fei-Fei Li and Dr. Nirav Shah.

- Developing models using speech, facial, and linguistic features to detect depression/anxiety from patient interviews.
- · Using unsupervised / semi-supervised pretraining to increase performance on small medical datasets.

Language and Cognition Lab

Stanford, CA

Jan. 2019 - present

2020

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2020

- Analyzing first-person infant headcam videos using computer vision algorithms under Prof. Michael Frank.
- Used human face and pose estimation algorithms to examine longitudinal trends in infants' visual scenes.
- Work accepted as a talk, presented at Conference of the Cognitive Science Society 2020.

Work Experience_

Amazon Fire TV Gahanna, OH (virtual)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020

- Developed a web portal using React/Node/Typescript that now serves as a hub for onboarding partners such as Hulu and Youtube TV.
- Worked closely with engineers and manager to design intuitive, user-friendly workflows for data entry and verification.

CS 198 Teaching Program Stanford, CA

• Taught weekly discussion section and office hours for 3+ quarters of CS 106B (programming abstractions.)

• Worked with sectionees to create elegant, efficient solutions to data structures and recursion problems.

Projects.

SECTION LEADER

Interactive Timbre Exploration link →

USING VARIATIONAL AUTOENCODERS (VAES) TO INTERACTIVELY VARY THE MUSICAL TIMBRE (TONE) OF AN NOTE. 2021

Smart Glove link →

RASPBERRY PI-POWERED SMART GLOVE TO CONTROL IOT DEVICES. WON AWARD IN INTERHACKT HACKATHON. 2020

Org-Twitter link →

 ${\sf EMACS\ PACKAGE\ TO\ TWEET\ SNIPPETS\ AND\ THREADS\ DIRECTLY\ FROM\ YOUR\ ORG-MODE\ NOTES.}$

Skills

Proficient Python, PyTorch, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js, C/C++

Some experience Neo4j, WebPPL, Lisp, Bash, Swift, Java

SEPTEMBER 12, 2021 KETAN AGRAWAL · RÉSUMÉ